John Olatubosun - Software Engineer

toluolatubosun@gmail.com; +2349084512241

LINKS	https://www.linkedin.com/in/john-olatubosun/ https://toluolatubosun.com	https://medium.com/@toluolatubosun https://github.com/toluolatubosun		
PROFILE	Resourceful Software Engineer with experience in Frontend and Backend Development, Mobile Development, Cloud Engineering, and Machine Learning. I have a verifiable history of designing and deploying cloud-based solutions and back-end features that optimize business performance. I have successfully demonstrated first-rate competence in building and integrating REST and GraphQL APIs, using cloud platforms, version control software, third-party services and working on AI/ML models			

EXPERIENCE

Oct 2023 - Present Software Engineer I - Left Lane Technologies

June 2022 - Sep 2023 Software Engineer (Part-time) - Left Lane Technologies

- Developed REST and QraphQL APIs for both web and mobile applications
- Deployed full-stack application infrastructure to AWS Cloud
- Integrated Stripe payment service to multiple applications across different use cases and application needs
- Lead a team of engineers
- Worked with a team using Agile Methodology
- Integrated various third-party APIs and services
- Projects: <u>Plugtent</u>, <u>Parseat</u>

Nov 2023 - Present Backend Developer, CreditCliq

- Optimized and added new features to the REST API used by the mobile app
- Worked with Paystack API to process payments and save cards
- Adding new features to an internal administrator system
- Made use of AWS Cognito for authentication
- Project: Credit Cliq

SKILLS

API Development and Integration Mobile Development Frontend Development Cloud Engineering

Application / Unit Testing Data Science and Analysis Machine Learning and Artificial Intelligence

WordPress Development Leadership Skills Presentation Skills Python/C++ Programming

NOTEABLE PERSONAL PROJECTS

June 2022 - Aug 2022 MySvote - [Online Voting Platform]

- Built a secure and scalable voting platform
- Gained over 2,000+ users
- Built with Node.js, React, and TailwindCSS
- <u>Mysvote</u>

Jan 2023 - May 2023 Gild

Gild - [Cross-border Money Transfer]

- Built an international money transfer Platform
- Built with Node.js, GraphQL, and NextJS
- Integrated Stripe Payment API
- Facilitated transfer of over \$1,000
- Gild

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATION

BACHELORS OF SCIENCE, COMPUTER SCIENCE

MOUNTAIN TOP UNIVERSITY | 2019 - 2023

- Graduated with First Class Honors 4.89/5.00 CGPA
- Ranked 3rd overall in academic achievement among the graduating class.
- Best Graduating Student Department of Computer Science and Mathematics
- Vice President of the Computer Science Association

SQL FOR DATA SCIENCE

AVITA | 2021

TOOLS I USE

Node.js	Typescript	JavaScript	GraphQL	Python	Django

AWS SQL MongoDB React Next JS React Native

Visual Studio Docker Rabbit MQ Linux

EXTRA-CURRICULA ACTIVITIES

2022 - Present Long Distance Runner

Dedicated long-distance runner athlete, demonstrating discipline, perseverance, and goal-oriented mindset. Engaging in regular training and participation on various long distance race competitions

2022 - Present Chess

Avid chess player with a strategic and analytical mindset. The game's complexities align with my problem-solving approach in software engineering.